Laubach Literacy International Records
Laubach Literacy International Records
- General Files
  - Mason, David E.
    - Correspondence, Idea Sheets, 1965 (Box 329)
    - Meetings, Wingspread Conference, April 25-26, 1966 (Box 329)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1967 (Box 329)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 447)
  - National Literacy Initiative / B. Dalton, 1983 (Box 447)
  - Name changes (Box 447)
  - New releases (Box 447)
  - New Streamlined English (NSE), Guide Introduction, undated (Box 329)
  - NSE, Prospectus, Word List, Achievement Tests, 1970-1971 (Box 329)
  - NSE, Test Manual, Language and Reading Skills Presentation, 1970-1971 (Box 329)
  - Newsletters, Laubach Literacy, 1958-1977 (Box 329)
  - Newspaper clippings; Jacksonville, Florida; others, 1958; 1960,; 1976,; 1983-1986; 3 folders (Box 447)
  - Otetela newspaper, Apr. 1948 (Box 447)
  - Panama, Programa Educacion Primaria, 1965 (Box 447)
  - Periodicals for new Literates: Seven Case Histories" / UNESCO, 1957 (Box 447)
  - Personnel, Loveland, 1971-1972 (Box 329)
  - Planning (chart), 1971 (Box 329)
  - Pride of Jesse Hallam
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 447)
    - Script, Sep. 20, 1980 (Box 447)
    - Television promotion report, Mar. 3, 1981; 2 folders (Box 447)
  - Principles of missionary journalism (Box 448)
  - Prison education (Box 448)
  - Programs International
    - Colombia, 1965-1966 (Box 329)
    - Guatemala, 1963-1965 (Box 329)
    - Mexico, 1966-1967 (Box 329)
    - Nigeria, 1964 (Box 329)
    - Ramallah (Jordan), 1962-1967 (Box 329)
  - Projects, 1965-1966 (Box 329)
  - Proposals; budget data; contract, 1968-1971 (Box 329)
  - Publications (Box 458)
  - Quincy," Loss for Words
    - Responses, 1983; 2 folders (Box 448)
    - Script, 1982 (Box 448)
  - Rauschenbusch, Walter / Robert T. Handy (Box 448)
  - Report on experiment in motivating functional illiterates to learn, 1968-1969 (Box 448)
  - Reports, literacy, 1960-1967 (Box 329)
  - Shah, S.Y. The American Interest in Indian Adult Education: Laubach Era (1955-1970), Apr. 1989 (Box 448)
  - So He May Run Who Reads. Blankenship, Mildred and Lillian Isaacs, 1984 (Box 448)
  - South Africa, Operation Upgrade, Jun. 1972 (Box 448)
  - Streamlined English Combined Word Lists (Box 448)
  - Study of Volunteer Adult Basic Literacy Organizations in the U.S. and Canada" / Wurzbacher, Mark F. and Christine H. Yeannakes, Sep. 20, 1982 (Box 448)
  - Summer Institute (Box 448)
  - Teacher's guide for literacy missions / Blankenship, Mildred (Box 448)
  - Wall charts, Engliddish, 1960 (Box 448)
  - Wall newspapers, 1958; 1964 (Box 448)
  - Adult Literacy Conference (students), 1983 (Box 330)
  - Clark Foundation, See Financial, Grant Proposals, Edna McConnell Clark (Box 330).
  - Eberle, Anne and Sandra Robinson. "Illiteracy: the Learner's Experience.", 1980 (Box 330)
  - Financial, Grant Proposals, Edna McConnell Clark, 1975 (Box 330)
  - Financial, Grant Proposals, Edna McConnell Clark, Jacksonville, Florida, 1970-1977 (Box 330)
  - Hopkins, Maria, Teaching Helps and Reviews, foreign born, 1968 (Box 330)
  - India, Karthicappally, Silver anniversary (English, Malayalam), 1983 (Box 330)
  - Johnson, Beth. "Vocational Opportunities in the Literacy Field.", 1977 (Box 330)
  - Journalism Internship, Rachel M.L. San Miguel, 1977? (Box 330)
  - Koshy, T.E. "Role of Literacy in the Advancement of Developing Countries.", undated (Box 330)
  - Liberia, Postage stamps and literacy, 1950 (Box 330)
  - Literacy Directory, Onondaga County, Nov. 1984 (Box 330)
  - Magsanoc, Maria. "An Organization Image Profile of Laubach Literacy, Inc. in the Syracuse Community." (Literacy Journalism Paper), 1973 (Box 330)
  - Management by Objectives Program, 1981 (Box 330)
  - McNeal, Linda and Harold
    - Correspondence, Minutes, 1961-1972 (Box 330)
    - Friberg, Norman, Afghanistan, circa 1967 (Box 330)
    - Laubach, Frank C., 1965-1969; correspondence, publicity material (Box 330)
    - Literacy Information, 1962; 1967-1968; founder's kit, education bulletins (Box 331)
    - New Readers, English the New Way, circa 1968? (Box 331)
    - Teaching English As a Second Language, undated (Box 331)
    - West Suburban Literacy Council, Wayland, Massachusetts, 1967-1971; membership lists (Box 331)
  - National Ad, Campaign (Literacy), 1984 (Box 331)
  - Organization Chart, July 1985 (Box 331)
  - Outline of a Plan For a Three Year Literacy - Literature Program in a Particular Language Area.", 1969? (Box 331)
  - Piepgrass, Marcia Rae Nichols. "A Study of the Feasibility of a Magazine for the National Affiliation for Literacy Advance." (thesis), 1974 (Box 331)
  - Reading Achievement Program, 1975 (Box 331)
  - Schoephoerster, Dr. Hugh, Minnesota State Department of Education, late 1970s?; speech on illiteracy (Box 331)
  - Schools Tutorial Project (formerly Reading Achievement Program), 1975-1977 (Box 331)
  - Schultz, Minnie. "Where Each One Teach One Began" (1933-1939), undated; manuscript (Box 331)
  - Strawbridge, Margaret, World Literacy and Christian Literature brochures, circa 1956-1958 (Box 331)
  - Strawbridge, Margaret, World Literacy and Christian Literature correspondence, misc., 1947-1955 (Box 331)
  - Wilson Library Bulletin, literacy issue, Sept. 1975; includes article by Richard Cortright on the Laubach Method. (Box 331)
- Caswell, Robert F.
  - General Files
    - Achievement Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 332)
    - Adult Basic Education (ABE), 1978-1979 (Box 332)
    - Afghanistan, National Organization for Ophthalmic Rehabilitation (NOOR), 1973 (Box 332)
    - Agency for International Development (AID)
      - AID, 1968-1969 (Box 332)
      - AID, 1970-1974 (Box 332)
      - Press releases, 1972-1973 (Box 332)
      - Guide lines, 1972 (Box 332)
    - American Council of Volunteer Agencies for Foreign Services, 1968; 1971 (Box 332)
    - American Institute for Foreign Trade, 1968 (Box 332)
    - Bibliographies, 1971-1973 (Box 332)
    - Bibliographies, Latin America, Biblioteca interamericana de lectura complementaria para adultos (BILCA), 1973 (Box 332)
    - Bilingual education, 1968-1975; 2 folders (Box 332)
    - Brazil, Mobral, 1974-1976 (Box 332)
    - California Literacy, 1975 (Box 332)
    - California Literacy, Quarterly Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 332)
    - Catholic Action League, 1975 (Box 332)
    - Center for Concern, 1971-1974 (Box 332)
    - Committee Reports, 1975 (Box 332)
    - Correspondence
      - Africa; Hoyt, Elizabeth, 1970-1973 (Box 333)
      - Afro-Lit, 1968-1972 (Box 333)
      - Borei, Swen, 1973-1974 (Box 333)
      - Christian Service Corps, 1968-1973 (Box 333)
      - Clark, Edna McConnell Foundation, 1975 (Box 333)
        See also Financial, Edna McConnell Clark Foundation (Box 336).
      - Collins, Lee (Mrs. J. Foster), 1975 (Box 333)
      - Foreign Exchange Rates, 1972 (Box 333)
      - Foreign Language Requests, 1968-1976; 6 folders (Box 333)
      - Gipson, Priscilla, 1974-1976 (Box 333)
      - Hanson, Marilyn, 1975 (Box 333)
      - Information Retrieval, 1972-1973 (Box 334)
      - Intercambio 66, 1975-1978 (Box 334)
      - Jakes, Cynthia, 1971-1974 (Box 334)
      - Jones, Freeda, 1975 (Box 334)
      - KGEI (radio station), 1971 (Box 334)
      - Languages, Arabic (Box 334)
      - Laubach, Frank C. India, Rasalpura, 1965 (Box 334)
      - Laubach, Robert S., 1975-1976 (Box 334)
      - Lebedun, Jean, 1976 (Box 334)
      - Literacy Task Force, 1968-1971 (Box 334)
      - McMillan, May, 1972-1974 (Box 334)
      - Mason, David
        - Africa Trip, 1968 (Box 334)
        - Afro-Lit, 1968 (Box 334)
        - Brazil, 1967-1970 (Box 334)
        - Operations Crossroads (South Africa), 1966 (Box 334)
      - Mason, David/Johannes, Phyllis, 1965-1968 (Box 334)
      - Michigan Literacy, 1973-1974 (Box 334)
      - Mohr, Sidney & Louise, 1970-1971 (Box 334)
      - Morris, Fred, 1970-1974 (Box 334)
      - Nace, Morton, 1972-1976 (Box 334)
      - National Affilication for Literact Advance (NALA)
        - [General], 1973-1974; 3 folders (Box 334)
        - Directory, 1974 (Box 334)
        - Gipson, Priscilla, 1973-1974 (Box 334)
        - Metro Expansion, 1973; 1974; 2 folders (Box 335)
        - Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 335)
        - Rourke, Robert, 1975; 2 folders (Box 335)
      - National Center for Voluntary Action (NCVA), 1973 (Box 335)
      - New Streamlined English, 1973-1975 (Box 335)
      - Newland, Phyllis, 1973-1976 (Box 335)
      - Organization of American States (OAS); Shepard, Marietta Daniels, 1970-1973 (Box 335)
      - Overseas Education Fund (OEF), 1970-1974; newsletter, Intercambio (Box 335)
      - Personnel; Hostetler, David, 1970-1972 (Box 335)
      - Pitts, Edward H., 1968-1976; 2 folders (Box 335)
      - Pitts, Edward H., 1969-1972; assistantships (Box 335)
      - Policy, 1968-1971 (Box 335)
      - Primers, Spanish, 1974 (Box 335)
      - Public Information and Promotion (PIP), 1965 (Box 335)
      - Ross, Emily, 1976 (Box 335)
      - Schunk, Jack, 1967-1969 (Box 335)
      - Shami, Jamil/Mason, David, 1967-1970 (Box 335)
      - Shearer, Mrs. L. R., 1968-1969 (Box 335)
      - Shumate, Hazel, 1968 (Box 335)
      - Spanish Catholic Center, 1974 (Box 335)
      - Story of Jesus, 1970-1975 (Box 335)
      - Student Evaluation Forms, 1974 (Box 335)
      - UNESCO Prize, 1971-1973 (Box 335)
      - Wilson, J. Christy Jr./Mason, David, 1967-1968 (Box 335)
    - Editorial Committee, 1973 (Box 336)
    - Editorial Committee, 1975 (Box 336)
    - Educational T.V, 1973 (Box 336)
    - ESOL/TESOL, 1975 (Box 336)
    - Financial
      - Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1973 (Box 336)
      - Grant Proposals, 1970-1975; 2 folders (Box 336)
      - Grant proposal guidelines, 1975 (Box 336)
      - Grant proposals, Lilly Endowment, 1973 (Box 336)
    - Games/stimulation, film catalogs, undated (Box 336)
    - Goals and Objectives, 1975-1976 (Box 336)
    - Gordon, Sol. Birth Control in South America, 1972 (Box 336)
    - Hunger, circa 1973 (Box 336)
    - Information Files
      - 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 336)
      - Afghanistan, 1967; 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 336)
      - Africa (Box 336)
      - Argentina (Box 336)
      - Asia (Box 336)
      - Australia/New Zealand (Box 336)
      - Bolivia (Box 336)
      - Botswana (Box 336)
      - Brazil (Box 337)
      - British Guiana (Box 337)
      - Canada (Box 337)
      - Central and Latin America, 2 folders (Box 337)
      - Chile (Box 337)
      - China (Box 337)
      - Colombia, 2 folders (Box 337)
      - Colombia, 1974; 1977-1978 (Box 337)
      - Colombia newsletters, 1968-1970 (Box 337)
      - Colombia newsletters, Colombia Today, 1967-1976 (Box 337)
      - Congo Republic (Box 337)
      - Costa Rica (Box 337)
      - Cuba (Box 337)
      - Dominican Republic (Box 337)
      - Dahomey (Box 337)
      - East Pakistan (Box 338)
      - Ecuador (Box 338)
      - Egypt (United Arab Republic) (Box 338)
      - El Salvador (Box 338)
      - Ethiopia (Box 338)
      - Europe (Box 338)
      - Ghana (Box 338)
      - Guatemala (Box 338)
      - Guinea (Box 338)
      - Haiti (Box 338)
      - Honduras (Box 338)
      - Indonesia (Box 338)
      - Iran (Box 338)
      - Israel (Box 338)
      - Ivory Coast (Box 338)
      - Jamaica (Box 338)
      - Japan (Box 338)
      - Jordan (Box 338)
      - Kenya (Box 338)
      - Korea (Box 338)
      - Liberia (Box 338)
      - Malawi (Box 338)
      - Mexico (Box 338)
      - Mexico, Newsletters, Mexico Newsletter, 1973-1975 (Box 338)
      - Nepal (Box 338)
      - Nicaragua (Box 338)
      - Niger (Box 338)
      - Nigeria (Box 338)
      - Panama (Box 338)
      - Paraguay (Box 339)
      - Peru (Box 339)
      - Philippines (Box 339)
      - Puerto Rico (Box 339)
      - Rhodesia (Box 339)
      - Scripts, Slide Shows, Talks, 1970-1973 (Box 339)
      - South Africa (Box 339)
      - South Vietnam (Box 339)
      - Tanzania (Box 339)
      - Thailand (Box 339)
      - Tunisia (Box 339)
      - Upper Volta (Box 339)
      - Venezuela (Box 339)
      - Virgin Islands (Box 339)
      - West Indies (Box 339)
      - Zambia (Box 339)
    - Intercom, 1968 (Box 339)
    - Inter-Institutional Meeting, Toronto, 1974 (Box 339)
    - Intermedia, 1970-1974 (Box 339)
    - International Afghan Mission, 1967-1968; constitution, finances (Box 339)
    - International Development Organizations, 1972-1973 (Box 339)
    - International Institute for Adult Literacy, 1968-1973 (Box 339)
    - International Planned Parenthood Federation (IPPF), 1969-1970 (Box 339)
    - International Representatives
      - [General], 1974 (Box 339)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 339)
      - Educational Objectives, 1974 (Box 339)
      - Kit Evaluation, 1974-1975 (Box 339)
      - Kits (Box 339)
      - Program Development (Box 339)
    - Languages, 1963 (Box 339)
    - d List, circa 1965 (Box Languages, Afghanistan, Wor339)
    - Languages, Spanish (Box 339)
    - Laubach, Robert S., articles (Box 339)
    - Management Cluster, 1975 (Box 339)
    - Mexico, Alfalit, 1970-1976 (Box 340)
    - Michigan Literacy, 1976 (Box 340)
    - Mission Aviation Fellowship (MAF), 1975 (Box 340)
    - National Affiliation for Literacy Advance (NALA)
      - Brochures, 1970-1975 (Box 340)
      - Conferences, Oct. 11, 1972 (Box 340)
      - Conferences, Pass the Word, May 5-8,1974 (Box 340)
      - Executive Committee meeting, June 21-23, 1973 (Box 340)
      - Executive Committee meeting, June 18-19, 1975 (Box 340)
      - Executive Committee meeting, Jan. 22-24, 1976 (Box 340)
      - International Representatives (IRs), 1974 (Box 340)
      - Lutheran Church Women, 1974 (Box 340)
      - Miscellaneous, 1973-1976; 2 folders (Box 340)
      - Newsletters, 1976 (Box 340)
      - Proposals, 1973 (Box 341)
      - Public Relations Kit, 1974 (Box 341)
      - Publishing, 1972-1973 (Box 341)
      - Silvia, Adelaide (Executive Secretary), 1976 (Box 341)
      - Southern California, 1968-1969; address list (Box 341)
    - New Readers Press, 1973-1975 (Box 341)
    - Newsletters, Dialogue, 1969-1970 (Box 341)
    - Newsletters, India, Literacy Today, 1971-1973 (Box 341)
    - Newsletters, India, miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Box 341)
    - Norma Burkhart Memorial Fund, 1975 (Box 341)
    - Oregon Literacy Inc., 1975 (Box 341)
    - Partners of the Alliance (Americas), 1968-1974 (Box 341)
    - Peace Corps (Box 341)
    - Personnel
      - [General], 1969-1974 (Box 341)
      - Achievement Reports, 1975 (Box 341)
      - Directories, 1975-1976 (Box 341)
      - Goals and Objectives, 1974-1975 (Box 341)
      - Novakouski, Dianne M., 1969-1970 (Box 341)
      - Rourke, Robert J., 1976 (Box 341)
      - Socha, Barbara Wilsey, 1975 (Box 341)
    - Primers, Spanish, Guia Para Instructores (Box 341)
    - Program Model, 1973 (Box 341)
    - Proposals
      - Colombia, 1964-1967 (Box 341)
      - Jacksonville, Florida, IMPACT, 1970 (Box 341)
    - Public Information and Promotion (PIP)
      - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 341)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1974; 2 folders (Box 342)
    - Publishing Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 342)
    - Responsibility Cluster, 1973-1974 (Box 342)
    - Right to Read (R2R), 1973-1974 (Box 342)
    - Spanish material, catalogs, primers (Box 342)
    - Staff meeting minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 342)
    - Summer Association, 1974 (Box 342)
    - Summer Institute of Linguistics, 1973 (Box 342)
    - Summer Institute of Literacy, 1968 (Box 342)
    - Technical Assistance Information Clearing House (TAICH), 1970-1974 (Box 342)
    - UNICEF, 1968-1973 (Box 342)
    - Volunteer Programs and Appeal, 1969-1971 (Box 342)
    - World Education, 1971-1974; 2 folders (Box 342)
    - World Literacy of Canada, 1972-1974 (Box 342)
    - World Vision International, 1971-1976 (Box 342)
    - YMCA, Syracuse, New York, 1971 (Box 342)
  - Programs International
    - Brazil
      - [General], 1973-1983 (Box 454)
      - Demidal
        - [General], 1976-1977 (Box 342)
        - Financial, 1974-1979 (Box 342)
        - Financial, Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 342)
        - Fund raising, 1976 (Box 343)
        - PLAL Report, 1977-1979 (Box 343)
        - Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 343)
      - Financial, 1973-1980 (Box 343)
      - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 343)
      - Publishing, 1975 (Box 343)
    - Colombia
      - [General], 1962-1966 (Box 454)
      - [General], 1966-1976; 3 folders (Box 343)
      - Medellin (Spanish/English), 1964-1966 (Box 458)
      - Posters, 3 items (Box 458)
      - Primers, circa 1972 (Box 343)
      - Scrapbook, Medellin; May McMillan, 1967 (Box 454)
    - Correspondence
      - [General], 1967-1972; 2 folders (Box 343)
      - [General], 1969-1973; 1979; 15 folders (Box 344)
      - Afghanistan, 1964-1973 (Box 344)
      - Afghanistan, 1968-1977; 4 folders (Box 345)
      - Afghanistan; Friberg, Norman, 1966-1974 (Box 345)
      - Afro-Lit, 1970-1972 (Box 345)
      - Brazil
        - [General], 1968-1972; 3 folders (Box 345)
        - Certification Requirements (Box 345)
        - Demidal, 1972-1973 (Box 345)
        - Fundo de Alfabetizacao, 1967-1970 (Box 345)
      - Colombia
        - [General], 1964-1973; 5 folders (Box 346)
        - Medellin, 1966-1969; 5 folders (Box 346)
        - Medellin; Mason, David, Oct. 1966-Dec. 1967 (Box 346)
        - Medellin; Mason, David, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 347)
        - Medellin Agreement, 1973-1974 (Box 347)
        - Bahamonde, Wesceslao, 1964-1969 (Box 347)
        - Dreyfus, Joan, 1970 (Box 347)
        - Friedman, Robert, 1968-1972 (Box 347)
        - Gross, Emma, 1970-1972 (Box 347)
        - Jones, Freeda, 1969-1974 (Box 347)
        - Literacy History, 1965-1966 (Box 347)
        - Ponce, Luis, 1967-1972; 2 folders (Box 347)
        - Sywulka, Steve, 1968 (Box 347)
      - East Pakistan
        - [General], 1954-1963 (Box 347)
        - [General], 1959? (Box 454)
        - Camilla, 1967-1969 (Box 347)
      - Ecuador
        - [General], 1963-1965 (Box 347)
        - [General], 1965 (Box 455)
        - [General], 1968-1972; 3 folders (Box 348)
        - Foundacion Alfabetizalora Laubach, 1963-1965 (Box 458)
      - Fountain, Thomas, 1967-1972 (Box 348)
      - Goals and Objectives, 1970-1974; 2 folders (Box 348)
      - India
        - [General], 1962-1965 (Box 455)
        - [General], 1970-1973 (Box 348)
        - Bengal, 1970-1971 (Box 348)
        - Calcutta, Bengal Social Service League, 1968 (Box 348)
        - John, A. K., Trip to USA, 1973 (Box 348)
        - Karthicappally, 1966-1973; 4 folders (Box 348)
      - Israel, Ramallah, 1970-1972 (Box 348)
        See also Jordan, Ramallah.
      - Johnson, Eugenia, 1971-1974; miscellaneous (Box 348)
      - Jordan, Ramallah; Shamy, Mohammed, 1966-1969 (Box 349)
      - Kenya
        - [General], 1957-1968 (Box 455)
        - Dames, J. J., 1964-1970; 6 folders (Box 349)
        - Mission trip, 1965 (Box 455)
      - Latin America; Shepard, Marietta, 1968-1972 (Box 349)
      - Liberia (Box 455)
      - McMillan, May, 1968-1970 (Box 349)
      - Mexico
        - [General], 1964-1980; 2 folders (Box 455)
        - [General], 1968-1972; 3 folders (Box 349)
        - [General], 1971-1974; 5 folders (Box 350)
        - Alfabetizacion Laubach; Mexicana, A.C (ALMAC), 1973-1979 (Box 350)
        - Froemming, Paul, 1968 (Box 350)
        - Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 350)
        - Morrison, Margaret, 1972-1973 (Box 350)
        - Renteria, Ana Maria de G., 1967-1968 (Box 350)
        - Tinaja de Megrette, 1982 (Box 455)
      - New Guinea; "Literacy Flies to New Guinea (Box 455)
      - Pakistan, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 350)
      - Panama, 1969-1973; 3 folders (Box 350)
      - Panama; Collins, Lee, 1968-1974 (Box 350)
      - Rhodesia, 1969-1973; 2 folders (Box 350)
      - South Africa, 1970-1973 (Box 350)
      - South Africa, Operation Upgrade, 1968-1970 (Box 351)
      - Vietnam; Fuller, Eugenia, 1972-1974 (Box 351)
    - Financial
      - Audit Report, 1970 (Box 351)
      - Budget, 1968-1969; 5 folders (Box 351)
      - Colombia, 1970-1972 (Box 351)
      - Foreign Funding (Box 351)
      - Mexico, 1966 (Box 351)
      - Resolutions, 1968-1969 (Box 351)
    - India
      - [General], 1971-1978 (Box 351)
      - Miscellaneous articles, 1966-1970 (Box 351)
      - Miscellaneous brochures, 1969-1971 (Box 351)
    - Information files
      - Colombia, circa 1968 (Box 352)
      - East Pakistan, 1955-1968 (Box 352)
      - General information (Box 352)
      - India, 1975-1977 (Box 352)
      - Middle East, 1975-1978 (Box 352)
      - Miscellaneous, 1969-1972 (Box 352)
      - A Plan for development of programmed instruction for teaching reading to Spanish speaking adult illiterates in Colombia, South America (Box 352)
      - Test Studies, 1970 (Box 352)
    - Journalism (Box 352)
    - Kenya, miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box 352)
    - Mexico - ALMAC
      - ALMAC (Box 352)
      - Adult Education, 1976 (Box 352)
      - Catalogs, 1969 (Box 352)
      - Course Results, 1976 (Box 352)
      - Documento de educacion de adultos, Postalfabetizacion (Spanish), 1975 (Box 352)
      - Document for Adult Literacy Education, Post Literacy Guide, 1976 (Box 352)
      - Financial, 1973-1981; 4 folders (Box 352)
      - Financial, budget, 1979-1980 (Box 353)
      - Goals and Objectives, 1975-1978 (Box 353)
      - Group Dynamics, 1976 (Box 353)
      - Guadalajara, Jalisco, 1976 (Box 353)
      - Guanajunto, 1973-1978 (Box 353)
      - Guerrero, 1975-1976 (Box 353)
      - Guide for the Development of the Qualification Course (Box 353)
      - History, 1972 (Box 353)
      - Illiteracy in Mexico, circa 1970 (Box 353)
      - Information file, 1976; 1978 (Box 353)
      - Instruction (Spanish), undated (Box 353)
      - Manual for the Coordinator, 1975 (Box 353)
      - Manual para el Coordinator (Spanish), circa 1975 (Box 353)
      - Mazatlan, 1976 (Box 353)
      - Meetings, 1971; 1978 (Box 353)
      - Meetings, Coordinators, 1975-1976 (Box 353)
      - Methodology, 1972 (Box 353)
      - Mexico City, 1977 (Box 353)
      - Michoacan, 1978 (Box 354)
      - Monterey, 1978 (Box 354)
      - Netzahualcoytl (Box 354)
      - Netzahualcoytl, 1978 (Box 354)
      - Newsletters, 1974-1978 (Box 354)
      - Personnel, 1977 (Box 354)
      - Post-Alfabatizacion (Spanish) (Box 354)
      - Printed material, Spanish, 1973 (Box 354)
      - Puebla, 1977 (Box 354)
      - Puedo Ser Mejor (Spanish and English), 1976 (Box 354)
      - Questionnaires (Box 354)
      - Reports, 1968-1978; 6 folders (Box 354)
      - San Jeronimo, 1978 (Box 354)
      - San Luis Potosi, 1975-1976 (Box 355)
      - Technical Education, 1974 (Box 355)
      - Tijuana, 1975-1978 (Box 355)
      - Training, 1975-1978 (Box 355)
      - Veracruz, 1975-1978 (Box 355)
      - Work Plans, 1978 (Box 355)
      - Yucatan, 1975-1976 (Box 355)
      - Yucatan, 1978 (Box 355)
    - Mexico - General
      - Information File, circa 1970-1978; 3 folders (Box 355)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960-1971; 3 folders (Box 355)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, reports, 1971-1973 (Box 355)
      - Miscellaneous financial, primers, sales, Laubach Hymn, 1971-1973 (Box 355)
      - Morales, 1975 (Box 355)
      - Primers, Spanish (Box 356)
      - Reports, 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 356)
      - Reports, Working toward change in cooperation with the farmers of the Tarascan Region of Mexico, 1969 (Box 356)
      - Newsletters
        - Brazil, Demidal, 1975-1979 (Box 356)
        - Colombia, Boletin, 1971-1972 (Box 356)
        - Mexico, Alfabetizacion Laubach Mexico Association Civil, 1974-1975 (Box 356)
        - Mexico, ALMAC, 1977 (Box 356)
        - Panama, Boletin, 1971-1973 (Box 356)
      - Newspaper clippings, Mexico (Spanish), 1971 (Box 356)
      - Organization of American States (OAS) reports, 1971-1972 (Box 356)
      - Panama, 1967-1979 (Box 356)
      - Primers, 1969 (Box 356)